J. Matthew Griffis (Matt)

Personal Statement

I make tech and life playful as a designer, programmer, and artist. I have a well-rounded background emphasizing critical thinking and logic, collaboration, adaptability, intellectual strength, leadership, self-motivation, and imagination.

I create interactive experiences about exploration and experimentation, creativity, reflection, reaction, and delight. I'm also a passionate musician and writer.

Education

Parsons The New School for Design--NYC, NY (May 2014) Master of Fine Arts in Design and Technology

St. John's College--Santa Fe, NM (May 2008) Bachelor of Arts in Liberal Arts

Work Experience

TreSensa, Inc.—Seattle, WA (remote) (Sept. 2014 - present)
Consultant

Write/edit articles and code samples (JavaScript/HTML5) to document the TreSensa Game Engine (TGE) for mobile web.

Salk School of Science--NYC, NY (Feb. 2014 - May 2014)
Game Design and Programming Instructor
Taught game development to middle-school students, with a focus on programming in GameMaker Language (GML).

Parsons--NYC, NY (Aug. 2013 - May 2014)
Graduate Teaching Assistant for Interaction/Web Design
Assisted with an undergraduate class teaching the foundational skills of web design (HTML / CSS / JavaScript).

Parsons--NYC, NY (Oct. 2012 - May 2014)
Graduate Research Assistant for PETLab
Assisted the PETLab (Prototyping, Education and Technology Lab) with various projects to use games for public good.

Parsons--NYC, NY (March 2013 - August 2013)
Bootcamp Teaching Fellow (Web)
Taught the introductory web design class to new Design and Technology graduate students during Bootcamp in August.

TreSensa, Inc.--NYC, NY (June 2013 - July 2013)

Game Design and Development Intern

Assisted with game design and development for mobile web, using an in-house engine based in JavaScript and HTML5.

Seattle, WA

Contact Information

portfolio: jmatthewgriffis.com email: jmatthewgriffis@gmail.com

phone: 253-548-4641

Fields of Specialty

Game design/development--theory and practice, esp. digitally
Web design/development--hand-coded, responsive, mobile-ready websites
Writing--creative and technical w/ critical thinking and analysis
Music--composition and performance

Computer Skills

<u>Languages</u>	Software
JavaScript	Unity3D
jQuery	GameMaker
C#	GameSalad
openFrameworks	TreSensa Game Engine
C++	Adobe Illustrator
Processing	GitHub
Java	Windows / OS X
HTML / CSS	Office / iWork / gDocs
Arduino	

Awards

University Merit--Parsons (2013-2014) Dean's Scholarship--Parsons (2012-2014)

Leadership

President, New School Game Club-Parsons (*March 2013 - Dec. 2013*)

Vice-President, dorkShop--Parsons (*Feb. 2013 - Oct. 2013*)

Representative, Student Council--Parsons (Sept. 2012 - Sept. 2013)